Hi Preppies, welcome back to another
crucial lesson in our IELTS reading course.
Today we are going to master a question type that often causes headaches for
many candidates because the information is scattered all over the passage.
It is the matching features question type.
Have you ever seen a box full of names, like researchers or scientists, and a
list of statements and you had to figure out who said what?
That is exactly what we are dealing with today.
It challenges not just your reading speed, but your ability to scan for
specific names and connect them to complex ideas.
But don't worry, by the end of this lesson you will be able to handle
these questions with confidence.
Our goals for today are understand the definition and key features of matching
features questions, Learn four useful
tips to solve them faster and avoid traps.
Master the four-step strategy to answer these questions accurately.
To achieve this, our lesson is divided into three main parts.
Features. We will look at the structure
and challenges of this question type.
Tips. I will share the best
strategies to save you time.
Steps and practice. We will learn the step-by-step method
and apply it to a real example about AI in education.
Are you ready to become a matching expert?
Let's get started.
Matching features is a question type that requires candidates to match objects
in a list with given statements or information so that they are true to the
information in the passage.
Matching features question type has the following parts.
Requirements, questions, features that
are lettered A, B, C, etc. and in a frame.
Pay attention to check if the requirements include the sentence.
Note that then you may use any letter more than once.
Each letter A, B, C, etc.
can be used more than once.
If the requirements do not include the sentence, note that then you may use any
letter more than once, then each feature
letter A, B, C, etc. can be used only once.
So after choosing a letter, we're sure that it's not the answer for the rest
of the question, which helps us to save time when
finding out the answers to the next questions.
Once you know the main parts of this question type, you need to understand its
features to come up with suitable steps for it.
In general, matching features is a difficult question type in IELTS reading
because questions do not follow the order of information in the passage.
Features are also organized randomly.
The number of features is usually fewer than the number of questions.
Therefore, I'm going to give you four useful tips for matching features.
Firstly, features are usually proper names, so they serve as keywords, helping
us locate information areas effectively.
If the requirements don't include the sentence, you may use any letter more
than once, you can cross out the chosen features, because there won't be any
features that are chosen twice.
Tip number three.
In questions that require matching statements with people's names, the passage
often uses their surnames when referring to them.
IELTS reading passages are often academic articles, so they tend to use
surnames more than proper names, as proper names are commonly used when a
person wants to address people that he or she is close to.
For instance, if one of the names in the features is Jason Brown, you may
find that in the reading passage sometimes the full name Jason Brown appears,
or sometimes only the surname Brown is mentioned.
Remember that foreign people's surnames usually come after the first name.
Let's move on to the last one.
We need to prioritize proper names or objects that appear less frequently than
others in the passage to read them first.
This is because if there are features that appear more frequently than others,
or appear in a lot of paragraphs, it will be
more challenging and time consuming to read them.
So you've grasped the basic features of matching features.
Remember the four useful tips I gave you today and watch the next video to
learn how to apply steps for matching features.
Let's start with the first one.
Step 1. Read requirements carefully
and underline keywords in questions.
This step is similar to that of other question types.
We need to understand the requirements.
It helps us understand which features and questions we should match them with.
The requirements in this passage are, match each
statement with the correct researcher A, B, or C.
So the requirement is to match the statements 1 to 7 which
describe findings or opinions on A, I, with the researchers A to C.
Moreover, the requirements include this sentence,
N, B, you may use any letter more than once.
There are 7 questions and only 3 researchers, A, B, C, so it is certain
that the letters will be used multiple times.
Next, we need to underline the keywords in the questions.
The purposes of this step are, firstly, it helps
us have an overview of the content of the passage.
Secondly, it also helps us easily scan and locate information
in the passage that matches the content of the question.
One more thing is that the features, the names of the researchers, serve as
keywords helping us find the correct answers faster.
Now, you have 20 seconds to underline the keywords
in question 1 and scan the features A, B, and C.
I'm back with some suggestions.
You should remember that when underlining the keywords,
you need to understand the content of the questions.
Here are the keywords I found.
Let's move on to the next step.
Step 2. Scan the passage to
locate information areas of features.
This step helps us quickly locate the information areas we need to read and
come up with suitable reading strategies.
Let's start with feature A, Dr. Dora Dembski.
As mentioned earlier in the video, the features are also keywords, therefore,
in this passage, you're going to find all
the areas containing the keyword Dembski.
You have 20 seconds.
Start now.
You finished?
Let's check.
In paragraph B, we can see the keyword Dembski mentioned multiple times.
You should also circle the keywords in the passage to easily read and find the
information related to the features.
However, if you only find the keyword Dembski in
paragraph B, you might miss important information.
If you scan the whole text carefully, you
will see she appears again in paragraph E.
Pay more attention to this, guys.
A feature can appear in different paragraphs.
We're going to continue with step 3.
Step 3. Read information areas carefully to
understand the main ideas about features.
After locating the information areas, we're going to read them carefully and
try to summarize the key points related to the features.
This will help us shorten and skip unnecessary information.
Let's read the information areas containing the
keyword slash feature Dembski in paragraph B.
When reading this paragraph, we need to grasp the main idea.
To do this, I usually underline the keywords in the sentence to understand its
main point and easily compare it with the questions, which is the next step.
In paragraph B, Dembski explains that while feedback improves teaching, it is
just not scalable for a human to do it every time.
She emphasizes that A.
I can create a bank of live advice based on expert pedagogy.
The keywords or content words help me understand the main idea.
She believes A.I. helps solve the problem of scale and provides expert advice.
Now let's get ready for the last step.
Step 4. Compare information areas with
questions and choose correct answers.
We can see that the phrases in Dembski's
paragraph match perfectly with question 1.
In paragraph B, she mentions feedback is not scalable for humans.
In question 1, it mentions guidance that would
be difficult to provide on a large scale.
These meanings are identical.
Furthermore, she mentions advice based on expert pedagogy.
In question 1, it mentions established teaching methods.
Pedagogy and teaching methods are synonyms.
Therefore, the answer to question 1 is A.
So we've learned four steps for matching features.
Please answer the interactive question
about the four steps for matching features.
In today's lesson, we have learned all about matching features questions,
including four tips for answering these questions and the four steps to follow
to ensure that you answer each question correctly.
Great job today and I'll see you in the next lesson.